And welcome back to another episode of Adventures in DevOps.
one of the things that I've talked with many of my colleagues about is just how it seems
like there's a ramp up in the number of incidents, production or otherwise, they've had to
deal with.
So today, I've brought in an expert in the industry, Lawrence Jones, founding engineer at
Incident.io.
And before that, if I'm right, principal site reliability engineer at Go Cardless.
which probably explains a lot about how you end up building incident IO in the first
place.
Yeah, no, that's absolutely it.
Yeah.
So I think we always, we always joke incident about just how many of our early founding
team were sourced from FinTech that might mean about the experience of working at a
FinTech company.
But no, I think, yeah, I joined incident about four years ago.
I was the first hire and joined alongside Pete, Steven and Chris, who are the founders.
between the five of us, we'd seen a large variety of incidents, both big and small, in
financial regulation and then also infrastructure and normal technical incidents.
And that serves you very well, it turns out, when you're trying to build an incident
response platform.
Do think there's something specific about the financial industry that lends itself more to
having incidents that cause bigger problems or is it everyone experiences incidents no
matter what vertical or area they're in and it's just something that stuck for you as a
problem that needed to be solved?
So I think in FinTech, you have an extremely pressing concern, right?
Which is that like money and managing finances is something that is both, regulatory
governed.
So you have laws that tell you how you should respond in certain situations and you have
obligations to certain, regulatory bodies that you respond in that way.
and that brings, that brings a level of rigor and discipline that you need for your
incident response that you might not find in other companies.
I remember the running joke with,
with my SRE team at the time, many years ago now at GateCutters was the next job that we
would be doing is a social media network for cats, because they presumably wouldn't care
quite as much whenever we had downtime.
When you contrast that with like a payments gateway where every minute of downtime is
literally all of your customers can't take payments from their customers, the type of
stress that goes into those incidents, it can get quite big.
from experience, the types of people that maybe own the cats and would report to your
support, you know, could be much more angry, like magnitudes more angrier than your
customers who aren't able to, you know, bill a couple of their customers.
I mean, given that I ended up going straight from Go Cardless into Incident IO and now I'm
on the page for our own call system, which is just as if not more critically availability
sensitive than a payments gateway.
think maybe the Cat social media network can be my next venture.
Yeah, couple more years and you'll do that venture and hopefully retire from there.
More of a hobby project,
FinTech is just one of those areas where not just like incidents in another environment
where maybe the website has gone down and after it's resolved and come back up, the
incident is broadly okay.
But there's a huge amount of background and other work that comes out of an incident that
happens in FinTech.
And I think that requires you to build up a lot more in terms of your incident process so
that you can track work even after the initial impact is over, after you've stopped the
bleeding.
Yeah, you need to go chase all your customers.
You need to go inform people.
You need to do all of this.
And the penalties if you don't do it are quite harsh.
So you end up building good muscles around how to run incidents as a result.
So I have to ask this, incident IO, you're not focused on only financial customers though,
right?
I assume there's no branding around that, but maybe I'm off base there.
incident is a generic incident response platform.
So you can think of us as, so our like most, most probably recognizable customers are
people like Netflix, Etsy, Skyscanner.
They use our tool so that they get paged when something goes wrong.
And then when something goes wrong, they end up running that incident through our system.
So the whole value of incident is that we're allowing our customers to encode their
incident response process into the tool.
so that we can help them run the process without skipping a beat, basically.
then, at least most recently, over the last year and a bit, we've been looking at how we
can use AI to help our customers actually solve the incident for them, or debugging what's
actually gone on.
When you receive an alert that says, hey, you've got some network failure over here, we
can appropriately explore all of the different parts of your infrastructure and go, hey,
it's not actually this service that's going wrong.
Maybe the database over here.
is out of resource due to a bad query plan.
And that's the reason that you're seeing requests go wrong over here.
that's the journey that we've taken.
And it's not just that there are financial companies using us, that we do have a lot.
It's mostly people who care a lot about what happens when an incident happens.
So making sure that they cut their downtime as much as possible.
And people who have concerns such as we need to be really openly transparent with our
customers and make sure that we communicate with them promptly and run the incident in a
way that they would.
enjoy if that or maybe enjoys the wrong word a way that they would appreciate if they were
themselves their customers.
the reason I asked about the customer distribution is because I'm curious whether or not
you see patterns by industry or whether or not say handling incidents is something that
becomes more undifferentiated work, sort of like doing software development at companies
or whether or not the amount of regulations or the complexity of the vertical segment or
even the types of customers that a business has to deal with changes the way in which they
handle incidents.
Yeah, so I think the answer is both yes and no, perhaps unsurprisingly.
I think as you become more mature as a software engineer, you learn how to engage with an
incident response process more effectively.
But each organization has very different requirements or needs when it comes to incidents.
If you work in FinTech or a similar area, then you're often engaging with your legal team
to try and figure out what your obligations are if you ever have a financial breach or
something like that.
But equally as you start scaling into like really, really large, large enterprises, so
people who have hundreds of thousands of customers, some of which themselves are large
enterprises and they have SLAs with them that are really stringent and those customers
care a lot about them.
At that point, you're engaging with different parts of the business again.
So maybe your GTM team and your customer success team.
just like in FinTech, you end up with financial penalties if things go wrong.
It depends on your context as a company, but definitely as you scale upwards, you get much
more serious in terms of how you approach these problems.
And even across industries, you see kind of broad patterns played out, right?
So I think everyone, as an example, think starts off with a status page where just
transparently talking about every incident as soon as it happens on a status page is
really appreciated from your customers and something good to do.
Gradually as you broaden your customer base and hopefully as you build resilience into the
system, every incident does not affect every customer and that can complicate your
relationship if you're publishing everything.
So you look for more sophistication in how you're running your response.
That is equally the same type of challenge that you have when you have a regulatory breach
and you need to inform a certain subset of customers.
So
a sort of a challenge to find the balanced area of transparency and also solving the
problem effectively.
I know you're not specifically in this space, but for us, the challenge is obviously if
there is a problem with one of our services and where I don't want to say we're in the
security space, we were providing plugin and access control.
So if there is a problem, then making sure that we're rolling out
solutions or fixes or communication to just the customers that are trustworthy is more
important than just rolling it across, you know, exposing that problem and then
potentially having malicious customers of ours, you know, attempting to do something with
that malicious data.
I know you probably don't have that particular scenario, but it's an easy way of seeing
that you want to focus the communication to the audience that makes the most sense and at
scale, it just doesn't make sense to send the same message to everyone.
if you just want to inform people as soon as you possibly can, if you're not considerate
with who you're informing, as your customer list grows much, larger, informing everyone
about an incident where only 10 % of the people you're informing may be impacted, arguably
you can cause far more harm than good.
Like literally looking at the social calculus of worrying 10 times as many people as you
need about an incident that's not relevant to them is...
is also not good.
yeah, it gets a lot more complicated as you scale up, as you say.
are you in AWS, GCP, Azure,
So we run across a couple of different providers, primarily inside of GCP.
So I actually don't know how a lot of experience with the operational support of running
technology and GCP, but in AWS, we get a lot of emails saying like, there is a required
action to be executed.
And you go into the email and the requirement is, oh, we're sunsetting this product, which
you have never used in any account in your entire organization.
And so it definitely has like a negative impact on the brand even.
for you to send out these communications which aren't valuable and they waste cycles on
having someone have to even filter them but read the email, understand that it has nothing
to do with them before even jumping into it.
GCP hit and miss on this.
mean, famously, Google loved deprecating things.
I argue whether or not that's good or bad.
But one thing that they do do in their communication, they're usually quite good at going
through all the different services that you're using.
And they'll only notify you if they're pretty confident that they've seen activity on the
API that they think that they're going to be changing.
So often, actually, my experience with GCP is it's usually very actionable.
They can go.
If I'm telling you about this, it's because I've seen that you used it in the last seven,
30 days.
And that usually clears up a lot of these communications, but I have much less experience
running in AWS.
We were, were GCP primarily inside of GoCardis and we've been primarily GCP in incident.
So they're my pick.
Yeah, I assume that since you brought that over and you're the founding engineer, that was
pretty much your decision.
when I originally turned up it was uh Pete, Stephen and Chris had been playing together
the MVP of what incident IO was.
honestly our architecture hasn't changed so much in that time.
It's evolved and become a lot more robust and mature.
But even now we are one big Go monolithic binary that we end up deploying in what you term
a modular monolith setup.
But we're doing that inside of Kubernetes now where when I first turned up it was just
One go binary, but running as a single process with all of the workers, all of the web
stuff ah inside of Hiroki, which was quite uncomfortable when like we had our first
obviously very predictable incident of like a worker going wrong that would bring down the
entire service.
And we were very quick to adjust as we went, but I guess this is actually one of the
benefits of having seen the growth of a company like GoCarless before, and then coming in
being the person kind of responsible for evolving the infrastructure inside of incident.
It's that you can go, well, I know that this thing is going to happen at a certain point,
and you can be very ready for those adaptions.
And I think that's part of what helped us scale very effectively in the first two years.
was making sure that we only applied the right level of process and the right level of
sophistication when we thought that we needed it.
I want to dive into that.
if some of your stack was using Heroku, my experience in the past has been at like deep
levels.
It's always surprised me how more successful companies can find a utilization point for it
because often it's missing some of those edge case services, which then become critical.
I see these things like secrets management, especially like anything related to
cryptography.
I just haven't seen Heroku be able to support that well.
So you were on there.
How did you actually decide, what was the turning point to actually make the decision to
switch over and really go for one of the hyperscalers?
think exactly what you've mentioned is honestly the thing that pushed us the most.
while we were running in Heroku, the application at the time was this Go monolith, and it
was running on a Heroku service Postgres instance.
And that hasn't...
I mean, that architecture hasn't changed.
We still have one big Postgres.
database that we look after in a much more mature way now, but that's in Cloud SQL.
But even when we first started, PubSub was the way that the application did asynchronous
message processing.
And that actually worked really, really well, but it meant that we were already kind of
half and half in both Heroku and in GCP.
And I think the thing for me that made it very obvious that we were going to move was what
you said about Heroku lacking various primitives that you want when you want to become
more mature.
I mean, especially when you consider we have, it's some horrible percentage of the world's
GDP is indirectly locked up in the companies that use us at the moment.
We've got some really, really big customers and they're running their incidents in our
platform.
So we have a huge obligation to make sure that those things are secure.
And running a Hiroki where you have just standard like...
12 factor auth and like you're saying up environment variables is not the level of
sophistication and security that you would want.
So gradually I think we were piecemeal moving things into what I had spent the first
couple of weeks at incident setting up as a very sensible GCP environment with all the
right security primitives and things like that.
But we ended up gradually moving to GCP secret manager where even though we were running
in Heroku
we would have our app using a security perimeter and service accounts that were authorized
just from the Heroku environment to decrypt the secrets on the fly as and when they wanted
to use them, which was a nice way of us grafting ourselves to a much more secure GCP
primitive without abandoning all the stuff that you would normally get inside of Heroku.
And we did the same gradually moving our workloads over from Heroku into Kubernetes inside
of GCP.
and then finding a way to split the traffic across and moving over the workers and then
eventually moving over the database too.
But yeah, I think there's always a push if you're ever in a Heroku environment or
something like that where you're just going, I want a bit more control over this or I want
a bit more visibility and I'm willing to pay the cost now because we're much larger having
a dedicated infrastructure engineers.
You can look after this and make a nice like paved path to production so that people can
deploy things effectively.
I actually see it as a cost reduction mechanism when you are given the primitives that
work out of the box.
You don't have to build complicated technology to say cross clouds because even in your
example using uh the GCP secrets manager and having service clients that have direct
access there, you still have to deploy the secrets for the, think in GCP, their JWTs or
their JSON blobs that have the certificate embedded in order to actually generate JWTs to
be sent to the server.
How do you even secure those and get those deployed into the Heroku environment?
Because if I recall, and still true maybe recently, there's no workload entity identifiers
for the individual workloads that are running in Heroku.
So there's no way to really secure those payloads locally to just the machine that's
actually relevant.
Yeah, absolutely.
And I think this was part of the migration path that we came up with.
So the first thing that we did was we created a security perimeter in GCP that allowed a
secret manager API access only from a specific group of IPs in Heroku.
anywhere near as secure as workload identity, for example.
But if you're looking at a halfway house where you go, actually, I want to be able to pull
this stuff into a different environment that's more secure.
and kind of like opt my way gradually into more of the sophistication that you get from a
hyperscaler.
That's a legitimate pathway to getting there.
And now we're in a GCP environment that is properly locked down and like, as you say,
using all the primitives that allow you to best leverage the security tools that you get
from the provider.
There was a little hesitation, I think, early on when you were answering which cloud tech
stack you were using.
And I don't know if that was because you have workloads running in the other cloud
providers.
Is as backup strategy or something like that?
We want to prioritize on using few tools and knowing them extremely well.
And for us, that means our disaster recovery plan has like a couple of different phases to
it.
But what we do is we end up running all of our infrastructure inside of primarily one
region, which involves several different data centers inside of Google.
So all of our workloads.
in the hot primary cluster.
They're spread across three different data centers in one region.
We then have a disaster recovery plan that has another region that we will fall back to if
that ever goes wrong.
That region is also within GCP, but we also have various different other requirements.
For example, some of our work with customers in China require us to use different types of
infrastructure to send telecommunications over to them.
So we have a ton of different constraints that mean that
we want to be running with backups that span outside of just GCP.
Now directionally, I think over the next year, we'll end up running our workloads across a
variety of different providers.
Again, I think that we'll be prioritizing GCP and a multi-regional backup inside of GCP is
the way that we want to run things.
Now based on your, like the name of the company and the product, I'm guessing you're, and
what you've said so far, it's really a focus on the incident management and I'll call them
standard run books, organizational run books for how to deal with that.
But I feel like you've expanded outside of that.
And now I would see it as, maybe I'll just for context, if I say things like fire hose and
pager duty, are you, would you say you're like directly?
in competition with those, because I know early on companies like PagerDuty, really
focused on handling the event and alerting for when there was an incident, but not
necessarily handling the flow.
And I don't remember ever coming up with a run book and throwing it in third party other
tools.
All our run books would be in a, and I'm sure I'm going to get some angry emails for this
and question my life choices, but we were using Confluence.
I think, I think what I'll say about that is have yet to find a better tool.
It's the least bad one, but maybe you can add some clarity to sort of how you're thinking
about it.
Because I know for bigger companies, as you said, if you're trying to apply a policy
because of either compliance or because of regulation, then following the run books that
you're creating at the organizational level is critical for resolving the incident, which
is of course separate from whether or not how you know there's an incident and what you
communicate to your customers.
the full focus of the company and why incident came to be was it felt to us that the
providers that already existed to provide incident response tooling were focused kind of
almost to the exclusion of anything else on just how to tell you there is something wrong.
it's kind of this horrible sense that...
the effort stopped to the point that your phone went off.
And for people who've been paged for hundreds, maybe thousands of incidents at this point,
the reverse could not be more true, which is that all the work starts at the point that
your phone actually starts ringing.
So incident.io was focused on, initially focused on the attempt to help you beyond the
point where you initially got paged.
And the start of the company was to plug into providers like PagerGT or OpsGene.
So that at the point where you got paged, we pull you into a Slack channel.
And it was at that point that we take you through the journey of actually trying to
resolve it and caring about things like tracking all the actions that are going on on the
incident, making sure that when you're coordinating with people, there's just one place to
go to talk about what's going on in the incident.
As the company matured, we've kind of built out various different other kind of adjacent
services that we think are core to incident response, but weren't always packaged with
those providers either.
So things that we built, so status pages.
One of the biggest customers using our status page at the moment is OpenAI.
So if they have an outage, OpenAI are going to post an incident on their status page,
which ends up informing their customers about, we've got some issues with this model.
And then they can prioritize what they're doing.
So that's a lot about helping walk your customers through the coordination of an incident.
But we've also built out the on-call aspect of incident response too.
So it's now the case that you don't need a PagesGT, you don't need an OpsGT, we have...
the mobile app, have all the telecommunications.
So we'll help you set up your schedules and make sure that you're doing all the things
that we think are really healthy, such as if you've had a really busy night on the page
here, we'll prior like propose to people on the schedule that maybe they should take your
shift the next day so that you can get some rest and recover and recuperate rather than
just keeping the same person on throughout the week until they're unrugged.
most recently, the thing that has been interesting in this area for me is
So I um lead AI incident.
So we have a team working on how to leverage AI to best help people resolve their
incidents.
And we have a product called AISRE, which is aiming to help in that space.
So what we do now, whenever you have an incident is we will look at the alert and we'll
set our system off to go crawl a bunch of different things.
Say looking at all of your GitHub pull requests to say, I found this alert.
Does anything look like it might have caused this alert based on
the diffs of the code that we can see and the timing around when it was deployed.
But we'll also check stuff in your SAC workspace and we'll also look at all of your past
incident data.
And one of the most useful things of this product is that we actually pull together
organically from the history of all your old incidents, how you've responded to issues
like this in the past.
And what we do is we end up compiling this ephemeral run book that says actually, given
what I can see that you've done in the past and what worked and what didn't, and even
looking at your postmortems on
what you said worked and what you missed, this is actually what we think that you should
do right now, which can include things like, this looks like a data breach.
You should be contacting your DPA.
Do you want us to page them?
Or maybe it's just, by the way, this service is really flaky.
I'm pretty sure this alert is actually not legit.
You can run this script to try and verify whether or not the thing is actually true.
And you can maybe even just ignore this and go back to bed.
But yeah, I thought that the runbook stuff is interesting because we have people who
source their runbooks in all sorts of places.
And while they may give a different answer on where they put their runbooks, there is one
consistent message with them, which is always that the runbooks are always out of date, no
matter what you do.
I think we've seen a lot of companies get wrong the reason why they're creating a run
book.
I'll say that that reason is often, I want to tell someone else what to do when there is
an incident.
I think the problem there is the people with the knowledge are trying to explain to
someone who doesn't have the knowledge in a critical or emergency situation, what the
correct thing to do is.
that's the run book has zero value.
The value you get out of making a run book is making the run book and understanding how to
actually communicate.
you're really onto something there, really critical, which is the fact that it's not about
what you think you should do in that incident.
It's learning more about the system.
And you're doing that programmatically through pulling in information from any number of
sources you mentioned.
I'm really curious about the technical challenges in actually achieving that.
How do you actually go and pull the information out of there?
No, no, I mean, they're all really good questions.
So what we do is we connect to a variety of different systems.
That's kind of the prerogative of an incident response tool, because everything in the
company kind of falls downstream into an incident.
So we already have access into a lot of different places.
Slack is just one example.
And what we do is we allow you to connect various channels into our system that say, hey,
by the way, here is
a channel that will often contain interesting things that might be relevant to you in an
incident.
So the one that is often a really good example is an engineering channel.
If you just have a shared public site channel called engineering where you post, hey, by
the way, we've changed how we do things about deployments.
We'll be watching that channel if you add it into the system to go, oh, I see.
There's a thing I've learned.
So if I start seeing an incident that looks like it's something to do with deployments and
it's happened.
just a couple of hours after someone's gone and posted it into engineering, then that's
actually very relevant.
So I'm going to incorporate that into my findings and use it to guide me.
But there's a ton of other tools that we connect to.
So we connect to GitHub, like you said.
So we'll look at recent code changes.
We'll also connect into telemetry.
So we'll connect via Grafana into your metrics, logs, and traces.
And what we end up doing is through a history of all the incidents that you've had before.
And also through a variety of background processing, we're continually trying to learn
more about how you as an organization have built your kind of incident immune response.
Like what are the things that you do when you have an incident like this so that we can
quickly guide an investigation to find all the dashboards that you normally look at,
surface all the relevant information, inform you of anything someone said had changed
recently.
And we do that through a combination of like, honestly, a lot of quite advanced like AI
rags.
Yeah, no, absolutely.
I just even want to go deeper.
So the data is in my Slack channels or in my, I don't know, previous incidents, wherever
I'm recording that.
How does it get into a place that you can actually utilize to identify what the new
ephemeral runbook should be?
Like, how do you decide what's relevant?
Are you a canonical thing?
As you said, rag, are you copying first level, like what data seems like it could be
relevant into
a set of rag databases and then using that at say runtime whenever an incident happens to
query it for those pieces of data and use that to then power some sort of search mechanism
back on the original source of data.
Yeah, so it is exactly that.
So we have this product called Catalog, which is your service catalog and a load of other
different organizational resources.
So people use that to model their organization.
So we have a picture of all of your teams, all of your services, all their dependencies.
We also have a picture for many people, like if you're B2B, maybe they'll connect their
CRM.
So we'll know about all the customers that you may have in your system.
So what this means is like we can...
use that as a knowledge graph to try and assemble all of the resources that we know about
your organization, and then use that to guide the investigation where, like you say, we're
continually background indexing the resources that we might need.
are you utilizing the APIs that are provided by say GitHub, whatever it is to funnel that
data in are you getting data from customers via, I don't know, any number of XYZ pipelines
and are utilizing that?
For instance, I can imagine a lot of customers, especially at scale may already have all
of that data having been replicated into your redshifts or your snowflakes of the world.
a variety of both native connections.
So we can connect directly to Salesforce or something like that.
But we also have this kind of universal adapter that I wrote a while ago and has since
been evolved a lot that we call the catalog importer.
And people can run this and connect to their custom service catalog, maybe if they built
it themselves.
And they run it periodically on a chrono or pull down all their data and sync it across.
that's how we end up keeping our platform in sync with whatever your internal in-house
solution might be.
But when it comes to something like GitHub and all the pull requests that you might be
making, that's us connecting over a GitHub integration, listening for webhooks and going,
cool, we have a PR here.
I'm going to pull that in.
I'm going to have a look at the diff.
I'm going to analyze it and figure out what are the key things that have gone and changed.
I'm going to tag it, keywords so that I can quickly find it if something goes wrong.
And we end up doing that for all of the different types of data that we index.
But the cool thing is, I guess, like this is the bit that is very interesting to our
platform is that incidents themselves are amazing resources of this information.
Probably the one of the best logs that you have, like when you end up taking the
postmortems that people are writing and you take all of the activity that happened during
the incident channel and you try and join that up with everything that you can then see in
maybe Jira or Linea when you're opening follow up actions and things like that, you get a
really complete picture of everything that's happened before and the state of your
organization.
must be such a challenge to identify every single source of data that could be utilized
and correctly the semantics of the data that's there so that it can be utilized in the
right way by, I assume you're using some sort of LLM.
How do you overcome that challenge?
Are you just throwing all the data blobs through your LLM embedding model and just putting
in a RAC database and calling it done?
the answer to that is like, yes it is a challenge and if you run the naive approach then
it isn't good enough to provide the level of accuracy and actionable feedback that you
want for an incident response product like this.
So the way that we look at it is it's extremely harmful for you to turn up at the start of
an incident response channel and claim that this is due to a problem that it is then This
idea of like actual like...
inaccurate assertions are really, really distracting.
It breaks trust in the system that you've built and it can also just be highly negatively
impactful.
Send someone off on a real wild goose chase that doesn't return anything of value, whilst
if we are who is improving the system for and where has it got worse?
Because often you can't really change this without at least some things getting worse at
the same time as a lot of other things getting better.
So this is everything from like having decent eval suites to building a system of data
sets of old incidents so that we can rerun investigations on them, which also comes with a
bunch of challenges like how do you run an investigation as if it happened at a particular
time with only the information that you had back then?
so that you can then grade it to see if the new system is better, but without you kind of
accidentally leaking information that happened after the incident back into the backtest.
It's really interesting you're bringing that up because actually I don't it wasn't the
most recent episode, but we had Andrew Moreland on from chalk AI and he was exactly
talking about what he called time traveling for fraud detection actually.
And it's a really interesting episode on that topic.
So we don't need to dive into it here, but yeah, I totally get you have a really useful
set of information there.
And I think they were doing something similar basically in the fraud space and in their
database.
What are you doing with this data that's coming in?
Is it going into some proprietary RAG database or using something off the shelf or a third
party provider or something like that?
So we're mostly indexing this into our primary Postgres database
And what you can do is you can get a really long way by just indexing this data with
pre-processed attributes that you can either use, so you can use vector embeddings if you
want.
They have several advantages and disadvantages.
Postgres has PGVector that allows you to look for vector similarity in your result set.
Actually, we found that embedding vectors aren't as easy to use and aren't as reliably
consistent as us just using tags and
But yeah, we do a ton of indexing things continuously, tagging them, some vector
embeddings.
And then when we fetch all the information back at the start of an investigation, we end
up unpacking all of that information and passing it back through what we call a re-ranker,
which is a concept that's quite familiar for people working with AI.
But you essentially unpack all of your long list of results.
and then you pass them back into an LLM to gradually shortlist to find the most compelling
results from the longer list that you produced.
And it's through doing this that we're able to search everything can return a pretty
decent aggregate of all the targeted resources within about a minute after the alerts
fired, even though if that may be hundreds of thousands of pull requests we're searching
across.
you're solving a critical emergency moment problem for people, you're actually able to
spend longer on that analysis and almost generate something similar to the existing
reasoning models from the providers that are out there.
They're running LLMs that may take a longer period of time to generate stuff.
And I can imagine maybe you have some sort of strategy for generating a first pass answer
and then spending more time.
in the background compiling longer, challenged answers that come up with using more tokens
or pulling more data.
Yeah, it's exactly that.
So I think we put a pretty high price on this idea that we want you to turn up in this
incident channel having been paged and we've got a fairly substantial preliminary
estimation of what's going on in the incident.
Now we immediately have to go back another iteration and we go target like other resources
and we go work our way through it and go, we really think that this actually means the
thing that we've gone and claimed?
So we might have a preliminary message that goes low confidence.
It might be this PR.
that we then actually were cloning down the code base in the background and we're double
checking all of the assumptions that were built into us thinking that this was the cause.
So yeah, over time, I think we go maybe anywhere up to five or 10 turns of that cycle.
most people will create an incident, especially a customer facing one, someone else might
create it and it'll go, hey, website's broken.
And for us, that's like, it's not very useful, right?
How are you going to find something that's going to help you with that?
eh Arguably anything that you have merged to the website or anything could cause that to
be broken.
So what we do is we end up pausing until someone provides enough information in the
channel.
Maybe they take a screenshot of the page that's broken and they drop it in.
So then we process the image with some multimodal models.
And at this point now we know exactly what the website is and exactly what the path is
because we can see it in the browser.
We've got enough information now so that's when we hit like all the heavy duty searches
and then we start pulling things in.
That's pretty amazing what you're doing there, especially even parsing the images or
pulling out the URL bar text to add in information to the pipeline.
I wonder if there's any sort of stat that's like when someone says, the website is down,
they usually mean this particular website.
in the past, the types of people that report that often are in a particular area.
And so there is still some sort of corollary that an LLM would be able to pull out
automatically via vector search.
So absolutely, and that is what we will do.
even if we don't have enough information to go searching through your GitHub PRs, what we
can do is we can look for other incidents that look like this one.
So if there's another incident in the past that went website is broken, we'll collate
together all of the information that we think was relevant from those incidents and then
we'll use that to guide our search.
So it might be that we can bootstrap ourselves to a position where we go, we're pretty
sure we know what this problem is.
And then that allows us to engage the other searches.
But otherwise we'll wait until we have a bit more clarity.
Because again, what we don't want to do is send out a very generic query, get tons of data
back, and then misguide people.
it's sobering almost that you said, know, vector embeddings or using a betting model and
storing it in vector database isn't the end all uh of optimized search results here.
There was another episode in the recent past where we were actually talking about how
whether or not semantic search for everything should just move to using an embedding
model.
And a staff developer relations expert from Pinecone.
So actually, well,
Maybe, but the keyword search is also still incredibly valuable.
We can't get rid of that.
you're basically saying, yeah, actually, tagging, human tagging on data is still the most
valuable thing that we could be doing for some regard.
mean, of course, you combine it with the appropriate format, but it's good, I feel like,
that multiple experts from different domains are really focused on getting down to the
point here, which is actually we still need things that we've developed in the past.
to be successful.
It's not just like the new model is better than the one before.
Yeah, and I think this applies to so much in the AI engineering discipline at the moment.
I think when we were first starting in earnest to do this, maybe a year and a half ago,
there were a ton of people whispering about how fine tuning was the way to get yourself to
a system that is like the one that's so much better.
really nailed it there specifically.
I've seen it similarly.
The fine tuning is just prohibitively expensive.
And so I'm not going to say rule out all the new technology options for sure, but you
really have to be doing something special where it perfectly matches the model that you've
got for it to really work effectively.
when you're in that situation to actually be able to utilize it.
I want to ask you a little bit about your evolution here because the company started at
I feel like a really unique time for solving these things.
Basically, when you started, the models available were just basically being born.
And you've grown at the same time, which the models have been really significantly
refined.
And I'm curious what the impact has been both internally in Incident.io, but as well as
the product that you thought you were building and the one that you ended up building.
So I think that you are absolutely right.
And actually, the models that we had maybe a couple of years ago, they were so, so, so
much different than the ones that we have right now.
And I think that ends up impacting both the scope and ambition that you have of the
product that you want to build.
But it's entirely changed, honestly, the direction that we would like to take the company
as well.
So I think we first started thinking about how we were going to use AI to really push the
product forward, maybe about two and a half years ago.
And we started with very basic things.
So we started with how would we automatically summarize incidents or how would we generate
incident updates so that people who were responding to incidents wouldn't have to actually
type them out themselves.
But gradually as we started becoming more AI literate, I guess, and the model started
improving and we saw...
agentic tools being released that seem to do a lot more than we've ever seen before.
The scope of what we thought was possible to try and help our customers with the product
that we were going to build has just increased probably every three months.
And I think the biggest thing that kind of changed my mind is the journey that I've been
through over the last year and a bit where we've gone from, you know what, we can just
give someone a really great summary of everything that's going on and examine all the
dashboards and just go, these are the useful things.
So eventually going, well, actually like,
we're pretty sure we can find a narrative about exactly how this stuff has worked and we
can reason about it and rule out the things that we think are irrelevant and the things
that we think are really relevant.
And we can propose next steps for people to eventually where we've got to now, which is
we're able to, in some cases, if we can identify the part of the code that's gone wrong,
we'll actually create a code change that we'll try and fix it for you.
So we have a virtual machine that sits there, or several of them.
And we end up communicating from our app and going, hey, please load up the code base over
there.
And then we have an agent that sits inside the code base and tries actually debugging
what's going on.
And then our investigation system.
is using a combination of that coding agent along with our telemetry agent and everything
else that we've got in our system to poke and prod and build up its understanding of
what's going on until eventually we go, hey, can you actually fix this?
And then we'll try and use the coding agent to end up building a fix, which we end up
pushing into GitHub.
Okay, that's pretty intriguing.
a really quite crazy security challenge.
I remember coming to Ben, who's our lead SRE and going, hey, how do you feel about us
pulling down other people's code and then running an agentic piece of software in there?
And the agent has to be able to run arbitrary shell commands and stuff like that.
The amount of work that we did on trying to just secure that and make it a secure platform
for us to run was kind of nuts.
Were you able to take inspiration from AWS's Firecracker or associated technologies, or
did you really have to spin this up yourself?
I I ask because we're in a similar situation where sometimes, not anything close to as
ridiculous as you're doing in trying to run basically the customer's code itself, but
realistically, we let customers configure stuff with maybe a programmatic point extension
and write some code.
And one of the best security mechanisms I've found is to just...
give it to a cloud provider to execute because their whole business is based on isolation.
And so if uh there's an isolation problem there, we're not going to be the only ones with
an issue.
So think, like, absolutely yes, the problem that we have is the latency.
So being able to connect really quickly and issue arbitrary code queries, some of the
repos that our customers have can be many gigabytes, large or small, depending on how you
feel.
And being able to pull that down and have that code base available so that you can then
run queries against it and trying to do that in ephemeral kind of isolated environments is
quite difficult.
so complex.
just would never imagine anyone trying to actually make that happen programmatically.
So hats off to you on that particular challenge overcome and execute it.
It would be really interesting to see how that evolves over time.
Yeah, no, I think Ben has plans to share a lot more about it soon.
It's been a lot of adventures in isolation.
Well, I think the key thing for us is this actually allows us to power some really
interesting product experiences.
And that's always the motivation for us here.
I think when you've identified something that is so novel in this way, it does create its
own sort of competitive advantage, which I can see is like not something you ever
necessarily wanted to start.
Like you didn't start outside.
You know what we're going to do?
We're going to figure out the all this infrastructure as code, you know, DevOps world
stuff where you build it, you run it.
No, we're going to just figure out how to run other people's code programmatically on the
fly.
And, and, but once you've done that, which arguably is the hard part, there's a lot of
like that can power a lot of things.
Like in one of these uh previous episodes, we were talking about how the company had to
figure out how to dynamically run customer code.
And they're not as, they're not gigabyte repositories.
But if you know what the code is and you convert it into an AST, you can then, you prove
that you understand what the code actually does and then run it in whatever infrastructure
you want, which is really interesting because it puts all the effort on building the
perfect AST generator from programming and.
one particular language and then being able to execute it.
But you get around a lot of the security concerns because you've proven that you
understand how the code is supposed to work.
And if it violates your whatever invariants you have on your code, they always know this
actually is like an instruction to an LLM to do something.
We don't actually want to run that.
even if you go into how do you get a code query to execute over a very large code base and
give back responses that are both correct and also do it quite quickly, there are a couple
of ways that you can do it.
You can either try and shave time off how fast you're going to get that code base locally.
That's one thing that we've done.
But there's actually a way more impactful thing that you can do, is
uh pre-analyzing a code base so that you have a map of what that code base looks like.
So for us that looks like actually crawling code bases and building up a bit of a map and
an understanding of what they are so that when someone has an issue and an incident we
bootstrap our LLM with some cheat sheet notes about this is how you should browse this
thing.
And that was probably the most significant impact on a very large code base.
It would go from being like four or five minutes to answer a question to if you could seed
it with this analysis.
Suddenly it's like 30 seconds because it goes, well, that bit's over there.
Yeah, that's the most ridiculous thing is that in order to solve your problem, you design
this technology which basically puts a whole fleet of other products out of business
because you had to do the thing that they've been trying to do, is it like you just look
at it, index all of your source code to be able to just find things that you're looking
for in that source code with Polar Class, et cetera.
That's often a challenge that...
large companies have tried to approach in the past they've gone for tools that
specifically offer that functionality but in order to deliver your solution you had to
design a solution from that from the ground up and that means you can actually target code
searching for humans not just for your agents to be able to uh...
identify what but what has changed what could be impacting a creating the incident the
first place
Yeah, absolutely.
And I think the same goes for honestly understanding people's telemetry architectures is
the same deal.
If you want to understand how to browse someone's logs, like you need to first understand
what logs there are and try and build up a map of like what logs are even useful to you.
And then you, you, whilst you get these LLMs and they're huge hammers for many different
tools, they also come with some pretty obvious and kind of like crippling limitations,
context windows being one of them.
Yeah, I don't want to undersell that in any way.
The context model problem is never going away.
We found out that just you will never be able to fit the whole context in your window.
actually the larger, the more tokens you add in, the less value each of those individual
tokens have.
So you will always have this problem of I have too much data to utilize.
How do I deal with it?
And the interesting thing, and I think this may be a pattern for the episode, is that it
turns out we've sort of solved this problem many times before without using an LLM.
And if you first take that step,
to sanitize the data or clean it in some way before passing it in, then you're going to
end up with a much better result in a much faster time period rather than trying to wait
for Gemini to push out the next multi-million token context window.
Yeah, cosigned.
That's absolutely our experience with it.
well, I like it that it's like a logical argument against.
Can LLMs get better?
Yeah, probably, but increasing the context window isn't really going to be one of them.
I think the thing that stands out to me that I think was not true two years ago, maybe was
becoming true a year ago, but it's definitely true now, is I think that the models that we
have out there are no longer the limiting factor to us building these systems.
So when I think about the AISRE product that we have and getting it from where it is at
the moment, where it is like delivering value to customers, but the scope of the incidents
that it can deal with are
really like small to moderate and we want to get it up to even the highest level of very
complicated incidents and dealing with this so that it's accurate almost all the time.
I do not think that it will be an upgrade of the frontier models that allow us to get from
that moderate to high.
Almost all of the value that we've managed to deliver or the improvements have been down
to being more structured in how we think about the problem, teaching us or breaking our
system up so that it's more modular so that prompts can be more focused and then figuring
out how we can actually make
better use of the models that we already have rather than waiting for the next upgrade.
Maybe we'll schedule a follow-up for this episode a year from now and we can see whether
or not that promise is held true or not.
I think you won't be the only one holding me to that.
So that seems okay to me.
He's repeated this promise on multiple podcasts.
any,
if anyone is exploring this space, I think the key things take away are figuring out how
to actually objectively track whether or not what you're building is doing a good job.
And then hopefully once you have that objective measure, you can focus on trying to keep
things as simple as you possibly need them to be up objective measure proves that you
actually need the additional complexity.
And if you're doing that, then I think you can't really go far wrong.
that no one wants to listen to is that you still need to do the actual hard work.
Like that hasn't gone anywhere.
You still need to know exactly what you're doing and do it the right way and think through
that problem.
And it's not going to magically land on your lap somewhere and you'll be able to push it
out.
yeah, and like there is just a huge amount of time that you need to spend using these
models and building systems like these to build the intuition that allows you to see,
actually there's this evolution to what we're doing at the moment that can get us to the
next step.
But yeah, there is no shortcut that I know of yet to get yourself to the place where you
have that intuition other than just sheer hard work and time thinking about it.
and here I was thinking I could retire soon.
Okay, so uh with that, uh let's move over to PIX.
I'll go first.
What I brought in today, and obviously you have to be watching the YouTube channel in
order to see this.
It's an Anker PowerPort Atom 3.
It's got some USB-C, USB-A ports, and it's got this nice little adapter in the back for a
two-pronged wall socket.
I don't carry, the reason I really like this is besides it's durable, it's light and it's
small.
I travel a lot and I don't like bringing around like the plugs to stick in to charge my
USB stuff and having to plug them in and after doing that for a lot of years are always
like really crap or really expensive like it's $50, $100, francs, whatever for actually
good quality ones that are now able to charge my laptop and it's just a real waste and I
found like the cheaper ones they just break all the time they're so unreliable and I don't
want to be on vacation or traveling for work and have my USB power AC adapter
break on me.
So what I started doing is I just carry this thing around and I buy uh the cord that
actually fits for the country that I'm going to.
So I have like a whole bunch of cords that match rather than having to play around with
like wall socket adapter, AC adapters of four of the different sizes.
And there's a transformer in here.
So it's like really just a cord.
like I was in Thailand a couple of years ago and we were on vacation and the power socket
didn't hold the plug in.
like your, the adapter was just falling out of the wall.
We had to tape it to it in order to actually make it charge anything.
And after that, I'm just like, I'm done.
You have a cord that comes out of it.
It's like really light and it stays in no problem.
So I absolutely love this thing.
It's fantastic.
Great.
mean, I'm going to buy one.
So I came fairly unprepared for this when I first jumped into the podcast.
So I think I've got two picks.
One of them is Mostly City, which is that we have a team here of people who love or like
fidget toys.
And one of the most popular has been this Rocktopus, which is a 3D printed model of the
rock with octopus legs, which you can find on Etsy that is endlessly entertaining for half
the team going through this.
And the other pick that I have is a lot more serious or a lot more relevant to the
discussion that we had, which is if you haven't ever read it, it's a book called The
Checklist Manifesto, which is about how checklists have been adopted in areas of medicine
and also other areas such as aviation and kind of the gradual realization of how to build
a good checklist and what's required to make it good, which has some direct relevance to
everything that we're talking about with run books, particularly around the idea that
until you have written the checklist and then run it yourself, the checklist is probably
wrong.
And yeah, I got recommended this by our VP of engineering, Roberto, who I've worked with
for many years, who used to be an SRE at Blizzard.
And I love this book just because of how relevant it was to SRE and everything else that
you might do in DevOps.
So you can get that on Amazon.
I would check it out, the checklist manifesto.
Yeah, the links will be in the down below in the episode description.
I will ask about the 3D printed octopus.
Is it like wood?
It didn't look like maybe it's just some sort of composite.
it's actually it's just it's just just plastic um And is the rock to purse because it is
the rocks head on top and it is just is just endlessly entertaining You'd be you'd be
really surprised
Is there like a particular model that you can go and download that from the internet to go
and run with it or there's like it's gone viral and there's like lots of different
versions available?
I would imagine it's gone viral at this point, but I will find out and make sure it
appears in the links.
That's a plug for if you are designing swag and you want to hand stuff out at conferences,
don't go to a third party manufacturer, just go and buy a 3D printer and your employees
will just go make stuff and you can go, it will be really unique, right?
That's a unique swag to give away or just use around the office.
It really is really unique.
Whether or not you take that as a plus or a minus, it is really up to you.
Well, thank you, Lorenz, for this awesome episode.
It's been great so far.
And I hope that we'll see you again back on this show, maybe in the years to come with the
updates on gigantic evolution in the industry.
Yeah, well, um thank you very much for having me on and hopefully it was interesting to
anyone listening.
Yeah, and to all our listeners, we'll see you again next week.