Welcome back to Adventures in DevOps.
I'm your host Warren.
And because today will is away this week, I have an opportunity to sneak in a sponsorship.
Today's episode is sponsored by Attribute.
I actually met the team and honestly what they're doing in the FinOps space is absolutely
genius that I believe actually everyone can benefit from.
They call it FinOps without tagging.
It's the first runtime technology that analyzes infrastructure instead of relying on
billing reports, exports, and tagging.
It's for architecture, ops, and platform teams that need visibility into product, customer
attribution, or insight into cost anomalies without wasting hours of guessing how to
allocate spend to shared services.
So there's no spreadsheets, no extra logging, attribute solves it all with just one line
of code.
They capture costs based on actual application usage generated from anywhere, Kubernetes,
databases, storage, and over 35 multi-cloud services.
In their UI, they break it down by microservice and even attribute cost at the database
query level, all tied back to the business.
I really find that pretty interesting.
Recently, they were recognized by six Gardner hype cycles.
I honestly have no idea what that is though, and are working with impressive companies
like Akamai and monday.com.
So you'll want to check them out and I'll drop a link in the description for the episode
that's attribute at attrb.io and now back to the show.
And today, I have to say I'm actually pretty intrigued by the guests that we brought on
because this is an area of technology that I have zero experience with.
We're gonna be talking all about vector databases.
And I feel like we brought in one of the experts from the industry, from a company that
has been doing vector databases for quite some time now.
I wanna say since the beginning, but I think she's gonna correct me.
So welcome to the show, staff.
Developer Relations, Jenna Patterson.
Hello, thank you for having me on today.
I know I'm really interested because actually in part of preparing for this episode, I
went around and asked a lot of my colleagues at different companies if they had any
questions that I should ask someone who's, I mean, you sort of just got into the work at
Pinecone there just under a year if I'm right, ah what I should ask them.
And they're like, I don't know what that is.
Yeah.
So high level, it allows you to compare vector embedding.
numerical representation of a piece of data.
And so And the vector database allows you find similar matches.
If you think about searching on, for instance, an e-commerce store, retail store online,
and you want to find all the shirts that are red.
might not all have the word shirt in the description.
So we want to find everything that is related or closely related, the most closely
related.
And so it does that based on a distance metric ah to find
everything that has a meaning similar to shirt ah or in this case a red shirt.
So it could be a blouse, it could be a top, it could be a short sleeve shirt.
ah And then it comes back as scored result so that anything that is close is going to have
a better score than the things that are further away from that particular query.
I see.
So you take the original request, so red shirt, and you're converting it to some just a
set of numbers and then using that to look through the database and get back uh equivalent
results.
So there's some upfront converting being done, I assume, when you're sticking data into
the database in order to store the numerical representations, not just the raw, say, text
properties.
Yes, exactly.
So at the beginning, you're going to ingest all of your data
So you chunk it up, and then you absurd it into a vector database uh ahead of time.
your users are querying, we take that query, we embed that query, and use that as a way to
compare against those existing embeddings that are in the database.
There's also kind of another piece about that, if that data changes,
ah or you get new data, can also re-up-sert that
I So, I mean, this I assume is true for all databases that claim that they're vector
databases.
How do you do the computation of figuring out what the numerical value should be for a red
shirt?
we do that through what is called an embedding model.
but this embedding model is trained on specific data that is for embedding.
And we pass in the text value, so that chunk of data or a piece of text.
In this case, it's text.
it spits out some numbers.
And it happens to be in vector form.
So if you remember back to like,
I don't know, fifth or seventh grade geometry.
We worked with vectors.
It's essentially a list of numbers.
But these are very, very long vectors, so very high dimensional data.
1024 dimensions in this vector.
And these represent different pieces of meaning about that piece of data.
um So it could be about the color.
could be, in this case, like we're
outside of the query, like the data, we might embed uh the product description.
We might embed product title or all of that together.
That could be part of our chunking strategy is to put it all together and embed that whole
thing as one piece.
I just have like a lot of questions now.
Like first and foremost, is it your fault that when I search for red shirt on websites, I
find things that aren't red shirts now?
I hope it's not our fault.
I understand you correctly that actually the model, I assume you're using like something
similar to an LLM to convert from the original text into what the embedding value should
be that you're storing in the database.
You're doing that because Pinecone has this capability.
But if you're using, let's say, I don't wanna say one of your competitors, but an open
source vector database or I think Postgres supports vectors now,
That responsibility is on the implementer of or the team that is actually implementing
search in their application, right?
uh Yeah, so there's a couple different approaches to it.
At Pinecone, we have two different approaches.
We support two different ways.
So you might actually have your own embeddings already.
You might want to manage that part of the process yourself.
And so you might use something like an OpenAI model to do embedding or an Amazon model to
do embedding.
We also host our own models.
It's an NVIDIA model for embedding.
we have a number of those uh based on your use case.
right now, we're talking about text, like product descriptions, product titles.
audio.
It could be images, any sort of data.
that you want to actually do a meaningful search over and find meaning as opposed to
specific keywords
is the comparison being done like in the database side?
like I get the part where you run it through an embedding model and you get back an array
of 1024 integers or floating point numbers.
that somehow gets stored in a database.
Is it being stored as a row value?
Is there a special format that the database saves data in?
Is this just an incredibly complicated question to answer?
This is for me, it's an incredibly complicated question to answer, but I can answer part
of it.
the comparison that's being done, that we are taking those two vectors and seeing how far
away they are from each other.
So if you think of a vector like this representing, you know, the red shirt and a vector
going like this representing like pants.
But maybe you have something a little bit closer.
It's really hard to do this as a podcast and just with my hands, ah visuals are much
better.
for those of you who are just listening, Jenna is attempting to draw vectors with her
arms, and if that somehow makes sense.
But I totally get like you have a triangle of vectors, and you're calculating the
difference between those vectors from each other.
And that's how you're calculating distance, and I assume you're optimizing for the
smallest distances possible.
one of the questions I have is like, you have a lot of these embedding.
vectors in your database.
And aside from how they're actually being stored, you still have to fetch some set of that
data optimally rather than fetching all the data.
I assume rather than fetching the entire database in order to compare each vector one by
one.
Any thoughts of how you are able to pare down the total amount so that you're only data in
order to do that comparison?
this is definitely beyond my knowledge.
um I will say there are strategies for how it's being stored and close the data is.
it's like the thing where I definitely try to pose this to people who come up with new
database formats, because there's always some in the space.
when I asked them about it, they were like, yeah, we built a new database format.
And I'm like, well, yeah, but really what you did was just use your underlying database
engine, and you just put a service on top of it, and you're calling it a database.
like it's really not at the end of the day it's just a relational database what I really
understand here is that it's fundamentally different how you're storing the data it's not
in arbitrarily row based information or know binary blobs that are being stored which can
be fetched fundamentally the vector database is storing data not only in a different way
but has to be optimized in order to find locality of these vectors and the the ones that
are close in distance.
I'm not a database expert, honestly, what you shared so far is still fine by me, but I'm
sure someone will call me out on it.
I do think it's interesting in that like, fun to understand like the underlying
technology.
And I'm like, as someone who has been here for six months, I'm still learning that.
It's very complicated.
our customers are like, they're learning it along with us as well.
And like, kind of what the strategies are so that
they can implement it in the best possible way, right?
I think this is the right word.
If you have an application where historically you would have done something like free text
searching in Elasticsearch, using an embedding model to calculate the numerical values to
handle a semantic search is just the progression in the industry.
You no longer need free text search.
This I don't want to say be all end all of the future of e-commerce websites, but it does
seem like there's just such an improvement.
in the strategy here from what was done before.
it is not necessarily that you're not going to use a keyword search.
You might actually pair them together, and I'll talk about that in a second.
then e-commerce is just a simple example.
It's the use case I typically start out ah But there are other reasons why you would use
this type of search, semantic search.
For instance, in your AI applications where you are getting your maybe you're chatting
back and forth with a model, but the model doesn't it has its own limitations,
As we know now, semantic search is about the meaning behind your query and your intent
behind what you're trying to find um based on what context the data is in.
um But sometimes you have keywords, or you have domain-specific language, or acronyms, or
stock tickers is another common one that we use as an example.
within your company,
You have product names.
You have your own company-specific language.
You have technical terms that might not be in the public domain and might not be trained
into those models.
we might pair a semantic search with what is called a lexical search or a keyword search
in order to make those results even more accurate, even more
correct
think you really stumbled onto a good thing here that's worth talking about because I
think where you're going is for those of you who are unfamiliar or may have heard of RAG
before, I think you're really jumping onto the retrieval augmented generation where
fundamentally, if you think about it, the models that you're using that are proprietary by
third party companies don't understand how you talk about your business.
And so how do you do the mapping from one of these models to what's internally?
And what you're saying is if you've uploaded all the data or you have hooks into your
knowledge bases and you throw that through an embedding model into Pinecone or another
vector database, using the magic of MCP or some other magic that no one knows about,
somehow the model gets access to this data and understands how to
use the embedding values from their own model to map to what's internal because there is a
semantic likeness between those things even though fundamentally the actual words and even
outside in say a dictionary those things are fundamentally different.
Yeah, exactly.
think one way I like to look at it is like we, you and I, like we have a spoken language,
we speak English, it's natural to us.
And so like if we can interact with our data and gain insights and find information using
the language we know the best, that's gonna be even better for our output.
LLMs have limitations and so, and part of that is it doesn't know all about our data.
And so if we bring in the knowledge, bring in the factual data, the authoritative data
into that process, then our output can be even better.
You may be the first person I've talked to that suggested that English was like a good
strategy for communication here.
I don't know if I'm suggesting it's a good strategy.
I think it is what humans.
ah I mean, there's just so much that's not shared as far as the context goes uh that is
just fundamentally lost.
And I can see how troubling it is to actually communicate in that way because we each have
our own internal view of the world.
And I know as a technologist, a long time technologist, a non-trivial amount of my
conversations have pivoted from talking about whatever the topic is to like a meta level.
Like, what are we actually talking about here?
you know, let's define some of these words.
There was a recent conversation I was having about the effectiveness of feature flags and
what came up, it started with like, well, how do you use them evolved into, it good to use
them?
And even if I say that, it's like, what does good mean?
And one of the terms that came up was, yeah, you know, if you have everything that's fully
tested and I'm like, what does fully tested mean?
Like, how do you actually define that?
regard, feel like it's a very well, I know it when I see it, but defining it is hugely
problematic.
Super hard, I remember back in one of my college courses a long, long time ago where we
talked exactly about this and how you a specification everyone understands ah and could
potentially be executed, right?
So it's not just that you and I can talk about it, but that our computer understands it.
So I think you bring up a really good point.
I think you're right in that it depends on who we are and what our experiences are and
where we come from and what language we speak.
be some of that that happens.
And I there are ways around that.
And I will say right now, I don't know all of those ways around that,
something that I think frequently comes up on the show is the mentioning that each new
release of a model public or proprietary is like having another child where they're like
so fundamentally different.
It's not like an upgrade is fun.
And so I think you brought this up a little bit is the idea where if you're upgrading
your, I say upgrading, side grading your model for one reason or another that
revalidating the embeddings that you got previously matched was coming out of the new
model to ensure that you aren't just gonna start getting nonsensical outputs.
mean, in some way you're upgrading the model because you think the new embeddings will be
better, but that obviously has an opportunity for unexpected Does Pinecone have a strategy
for dealing with that?
I I assume if you have an embedding model, given what the company is doing, you're
building the model yourself.
the Nvidia model, that one that I mentioned, that's a hosted model that we have, we host
it internally.
We also have our research team and they have created models for us.
So we have, The one that I am most familiar with is Pinecone Sparse.
is used for a lexical search, keyword search, with sparse vectors as opposed to dense
vectors which are used for semantic search.
What's the difference between them?
um a dense vector, you have, a vector of numbers, they represent different parts of...
of meaning about that particular piece of data that was embedded.
But with a sparse vector, you have more zeros than you have actual numbers.
And it is either a zero or a one that essentially represents, the frequency of our
particular word.
I think realistically, you, no one wants to listen to this.
You think back to when you had, you went further and you're like normalizing arrays ah
where you,
you create some sort of orthonormal basis for actually moving the data out so that you end
up with these arrays where you have just an amplitude at one position in the vector, which
makes it much easier to identify things in close proximity.
So you can imagine that you're not just letting the embedding model come up with arbitrary
numbers to represent your semantic text, but you're then applying some clever mathematics
on top of it to organize the vectors in a way so that
when you actually go and do a search, you're not having to pull out every single piece of
data from the database.
being specific about how you can utilize the mathematics to optimize your vector database
goes into some of the creation of these.
a lot of engineers got into, I'd say software engineering, or became engineers in the
first place,
they told themselves, and I'm going to say a lie, that they wanted to work on hard
problems.
And it does actually sound like that building, like compared to building up other
databases, I do feel like understanding the mathematics behind a vector database is not
trivial.
ah Yeah, I agree.
I am that person who like, I want to work on our problems.
I like knowing how things work.
And so again, I'm I'm still learning a lot of this, obviously.
think for me, that is one of the fascinating pieces about it is that it's math.
it's not easy math.
mean, like we we go to school for it and people study it for a really long time.
maybe the more fascinating piece is that we can actually use math to do that.
we're not discarding lessons learned of the past, actually figuring out how to use the
physics and specifically in this case, the theoretical application in a real world
scenario.
You know, one of the things that I originally had thought of when we were talking about
vector databases is that like, surely this is only applicable to LLMs.
But I feel like said that the e-commerce example that you brought up that really is about
doing semantic search is like a simple example.
And I don't know if I agree with you, actually.
I feel like getting the search right in e-commerce is like literally the most complicated
example of search.
when I say simple, mean it's simple for people to understand because as an example because
they shop online, right?
Everyone shop.
Most people shop online.
I don't want to say
I'm with you there.
I think there is something where it does seem simple in the service, but like as soon as
you get to thinking about how the search actually works, it starts to get very
complicated.
think one of the examples that comes up a lot for me when I've reviewed other companies
database architecture, like which type of database they're going with, or what sort of
indexes they have, it always starts as a generic problem.
Like, I have some data and I want to search it.
And I'm like, well, what kind of search are you doing?
Well, we have some attributes on each of the rows of our data or the items and we want to
filter by the attributes.
I'm like, well, which attributes do you want to filter by?
it always like each item has three attributes and you always filter on the first attribute
and the second and third are never used?
Or is it something common or something simple?
And they're like, oh, no, it's always, well, the user could give us attribute one, two, or
three, and we need to figure out all of the items that match one, two, or three.
And I'm like, well, that's
pretty much just eliminated every single NoSQL database out there because, you know, good
luck.
I mean, I will say in some scenarios, you can be very clever where you can just index all
three attributes, ah make three queries to your database, and then merge the results.
I was just going to say, but also your products might all have different number of
attributes and different attributes.
yeah, for sure, right?
And actually think the one that's more complicated is that like some of the attributes
have like an array of values, right?
So it's like, yeah, well, this product, I've used these commerce example, like this
product is a shirt, it can be in small, medium, and large, like the sizes that are
available.
And so when someone search sizes, you're not gonna have an attribute column that's like,
you know, small exists, you know, true or false, know, know, shirt can be in medium, true
or false, like this is just nonsensical.
So.
I think once you see that you're like, well, okay, search and e-commerce that that's gotta
be like the most complicated thing ever.
to say like, we've maybe collectively, we may have stumbled upon the limit for improving
search in that way by using an embedding model.
We're taking the core, the essence of what the search query is, trying to figure out what
it is and then mapping it to an optimized way of storing the data and a database that
isn't a row based where you're doing column by column matching.
uh or some sort of non-efficient index lookup like in a NoSQL way where you're just like
somehow you know exactly which item the person is talking about.
But I think that'd be pretty great reality get to where I just search for red shirt and I
get exactly the green trousers that I actually wanted
I don't know if you're familiar with like the dupe trend, the duplicates of like high end
fashion, where these like lower end cheaper alternatives come up with dupes.
So we see it a lot in fashion.
It's in other other areas too.
But what if you could search for like ah this?
this high-end fashion brand name paired with like white t-shirt frilly edges of the
sleeves.
And then you come up with like a different, the actual duplicate of that on this
particular site.
I agree that like these products that you're talking about and the categories and the
different ways that
It's not even just categories, but just the different uh features of them are very
complicated.
But what if we could actually search for those based off of, you a few words that describe
what it is, but don't necessarily use those same words.
you brought up, I think one of the major problems giant online search engines that are
dedicated consumer buying experience.
I'll say, I think there's one that comes to mind in the Western world, which is Amazon.
They have a huge problem with basically, I don't know if they call them duplicates as much
as counterfeits, where if you're not doing the manufacturing yourself,
that you've sent the pattern to another company and in their off time when they have extra
resources, they just print out more of your item without the logo on it or with the logo,
because they don't care.
And then when you go and search on any website for the thing you're looking for, even with
the brand name, you're getting the competitor version that's just not as good.
And people can't tell the difference most of the time.
And this actually destroys a lot of small businesses that are doing this.
I'm wondering if there really is,
a smart strategy here where you can use this for fraud detection.
And I know when I'm searching on Amazon, I always want like to filter by results where the
brand of the product matches the store where the product is coming from.
Like that's almost always what I want.
You make your thing.
I don't care what your brand is, but it should match.
And I always get suspicious when it's something else.
thoughts of like the...
you
Yeah, you can see who uses Amazon more than most.
Yeah, for sure.
But I mean, there is an interesting thing here.
Like, do you think that not just for search, generically for end users, are there primary
applications for a vector database outside of search that you see as like, this is just
now a new strategy where if you're not using Pinecone or one of the competitors to do
this, you're really missing out on some of the core value that could be being provided.
think you touch on kind of a hard problem.
You mentioned fraud.
know like, this is an area I don't know very much about, but I know that it is a use case
that we have seen people use vector databases for to find uh identifying patterns um of
fraudulent use and that type of thing.
I can see that that could be a thing.
do you know what sort of customers are primarily that PyCon is looking for?
Or the ideal customer profile that usually makes a good match?
you not pay too much attention to the specific use case in its uh company segment or
vertical?
Or is it you see something about their technology stack that is a good match for you?
I'm working with developers to help them learn and understand, how to use pine cone, how
to use a vector database, how to incorporate retrieval into their systems.
but I would say that like, one of the things we look for are people with, or companies
with
um like large quantities of high dimensional data.
So this is going to be your emails, your contracts, your PDF documents, oh images,
potentially video or audio.
need to get insight from it, whether that is a search result as far as like the e-commerce
example we've been using, or it is...
insights about a particular business unit and how they are operating or how they function
right before this, um I was reading one of our case studies about a company.
it's about a uh medical company that's doing research on medications and are searching
over molecules.
like that's a lot, right?
And so they are essentially embedding those molecules as vectors and then doing searches
over those in order to
gain insights and do research on their work in order to develop medicine.
So I thought that was really interesting just in that it's not just the e-commerce
examples.
I wanted to ask because you're on the other side, just like whether or not the ICP of the
potential customers, like it does match the types of questions or challenges that the
engineers who come to community workspaces to like specifically ask questions about like
whether or not they're like already going in the right direction and the sorts of product
areas they're focused on is a good match for that.
Or you see people just trying to use vector databases in places that like
have no reason to be used there whatsoever.
there's probably a mix of both.
see people who are, they've heard of a vector database, they've heard of Pinecone, and
they're like me, they're developer, they like knowing what's the new shiny thing.
And so they want to learn about it, they want to learn how it might solve their problem.
more ideal customers are people who are a little bit further in their journey, and so they
understand what is the purpose of it, what are some of the problems that...
that they can solve.
They understand that their problem fits in in some way.
And we have a team that helps them figure out how it fits in and how to actually implement
it at production scale.
Do you see them coming over from first the technical problem, then realizing they need a
vector database to store their semantic embeddings and then go to Pinecone?
Or do you see it as a of a nuance play on top of generic databases or even open source
databases that do offer a vector database?
And it's like, well, you know, if you're doing something in this space, you may be fine.
But if you need something more robust or at scale like
you would want to switch in a way.
Do
developers that I've been interacting with, I think they are first and foremost interested
in a piece of technology.
They know that they have some data.
They want to make their retrieval augmented generation pipeline more accurate.
so they understand that retrieval is a piece of that.
And this
that's all I really know about it so far.
uh There's definitely other teams that I work with that are definitely more in the weeds
with people and like where they are in their journey as far as like using a vector
database or coming to Pinecone specifically.
just go and use pine cone.
Don't use a, there's no reason using generic other vector database, especially, mean,
honestly, from what I, the research I've done that trying to build your own model to get
the embeddings working right is just such a huge lift in the first place.
given the challenges from ensuring like similar, like you can't just switch your model
from one version.
Maybe you're just going to tell me I'm totally wrong here.
Don't upgrade your model without also replacing all of your embeddings because the new
results won't make any sense.
if you want to swap out your embeddings, like if you've, you've done evaluations, you've
figured out, you've done testing, you figured out that like, it's no longer accurate
enough.
you're going to have to re-embed that data using a different model.
And so there are approaches to, doing some benchmarking and testing to make sure that like
your accuracy is in the right, the, the acceptable frame of,
use case can actually support.
you would be swapping out the model and re-embedding that data.
makes sense to me, but that means that there's a huge extra cost here to doing a model
upgrade, not just on like future searches and whatever.
even if the model is faster, you're building it yourself, there's some improvement or
using an open source one.
There's some driver there, but that's going to come with a cost.
And I can see that to be a huge reason to go with, just take that all off the table.
And if you know you need some sort of semantic search or some other strategy that uses
embeddings to go with a database that has that.
baked in automatically without having to think about how to do upgrades between models.
a big reason why we want to do evaluations and benchmarking ahead of time on potentially a
smaller set of data uh before committing is because you're right, it uh takes time, it
costs money to do this.
not everybody is going to have the time and money and expertise to fine tune or train
their own model.
I've mentioned retrieval augmented generation a few times here.
I've been spending uh essentially the last quarter, I've been uh not only digging in
myself and trying to learn about the different parts of it, but also different like
approaches to doing it and sharing some of that.
I've shared some of that publicly.
I'm doing stuff internally related to that and also in the future here.
I've got some stuff going on, but we are seeing people doing this and not fully
understanding what they're doing.
And there's like, yeah, right, exactly.
Probably multiple reasons for that.
uh Like we could go down the vibe coding rabbit hole of like how that is contributing to
some of the good and bad parts of this.
Like obviously it's enabling people to do more and to like get further into their problem.
But also it potentially brings more challenges than they even know how to handle.
uh
are vector databases being recommended by coding assistants as a solution for a problem?
Like if it's just like, yeah, know, generate me some code and it pulls in a way to write
to an open source database that requires embeddings or is that just not happening yet?
I do know that it comes up.
It does, it does propose a pine cone and, and other competitors and stuff like that.
one of the things that like, we have a challenge with, I, I expect other people do as well
as like, because these models are trained on old data, like it's using our old data, our
old document, public documentation.
so.
It isn't always the most accurate And so we do stuff on our end to try and uh encourage
those models to, or those tools, not necessarily the model itself, but the tools to
generate the right code, the most up-to-date code.
we're still a little ways away from it being always the right answer popping up in LLMs.
How about the LLM companies?
So companies that claim they have some sort of AI and they are really just an LLM that's
solving a particular use case.
Are they the cornerstone for a company case where like a case study that would be using
RAG more often than not there or is it just
There's a spectrum and it really depends on the vertical or market segment or product
area.
I mean, there's probably a lot of opinions there.
think that's like, depending on who you talk to on how that is.
think like for me, I see maybe the model companies are not necessarily advocating for
retrieval augmented generation.
I mean, maybe they are, but like we keep seeing these models get bigger and better and
faster, right?
But there's still those limitations that I mentioned from the beginning, right?
They're only trained up until a certain period of time.
It's not trained on your company data, your private data, among a few other limitations.
But those are the key ones that people really recognize.
And so that's where this
retrieval part of rag is coming in is like it's the way to give your model more knowledge
to give it more accurate and authoritative knowledge.
So if the primary use case outside like semantic searching or some sort of comparison
search, if you're utilizing it to extend your data from your own data or something else
that you want to pull in and that means you're using RAG, then if you're using RAG, that
means you're using a vector database, Oh, that's interesting.
It could be retrieving from some other database.
If we think about it, I think you recently did like an MCP episode, right?
So that's one approach to getting to kind of interfacing with other tools and services.
even like chat GPT, it can go out to the internet.
That is a tool that it's using to go get other data and augment your result, your output
with more accurate data.
one thing I noticed, especially with companies that are still incredibly technical, but
aren't specifically in any of the quote unquote AI spaces, is that they definitely get the
difference between MCP and rag wrong off then like the.
Byjection of how many of one of these things they need versus another one like I was one
of my colleagues is working at a very interesting company where they have a need to do.
Rag on behalf of their customers so they're they're pulling in knowledge bases from their
customers and they're trying to figure out how that interl plays with mcp servers and one
thing that has been problematic is they don't want to the data but at the same time a lot
of them mcp providers don't have this concept of like multi-tenancy like they understand
you as a customer can only access your data but they don't have a good concept of how to
group or sequester.
parts of the data into smaller and smaller areas.
from a vector database perspective, the way we've implemented multi-tenancy is through
namespaces.
So uh if you think of a company that is offering agents to their customers, each agent or
each user that has an agent would potentially be within its own namespace.
So that is a way to uh actually segregate the data.
I think you touched on something interesting though that like not all the companies out
there are AI first companies or they are not like well versed in AI technologies and
solutions.
And I think we're at the point where that's going to become a huge thing because all of
these companies there's so many more of those companies out there that then there are
uh AI companies that have been doing this for a long time, right?
I think we're going to have a fight on this episode.
I'm going to quote some research that I think came out Nanda AI report from MIT that said
only 5 % of companies are getting value out of implemented.
I'm going to say quote unquote AI, because I don't think we have AI.
That's a different episode where I got into that.
we can say AI for the rest of this one.
Aren't getting the value out, and it's just a
huge cost sync, time sync, resource sync.
If you say that going forward there's gonna it's gonna be interesting i can either read
that as you believe that companies will transition to having.
or all the companies who don't do it will be out of business and therefore the only
companies left will be one to do a.
I don't mean the latter.
I think there is going to be a transition.
But I think there's an opportunity there.
my background is not in AI.
Like me coming to Pinecone is, this is a new space for me, right?
So I bring the lens of the traditional developer who's been tasked with a problem and.
In this case, the problem these days might be a problem that requires a vector database.
And so as someone who has been a full stack developer, now I have to go out and figure out
how do I solve this problem with this tool that I've been told to use.
uh I think we're going to see more and more of that.
definitely don't mean that companies are going to go away.
Obviously, people are still running on mainframes, right?
And so it might not fit in that space.
technology sticks around for a really long time.
I think there's gonna be some change and it's not always going to be easy.
I wonder what the turnaround is for this because I see companies still claiming that
they're introducing agile and like, worse, they've done agile.
Well, I mean, okay, so the manifesto was like in 2000 or like 2001 or something.
I'm terrible with years.
I knew it happened before I really got into software engineering.
I think
Realistically, either companies say they do it and they don't, or they acknowledge that
they don't do it.
And that for me is like mind boggling because from my standpoint, everyone should be doing
it all the time.
I can appreciate the belief that the same thing will happen with AI, but if we're 24 years
out, 25 years out from uh the Agile Manifesto, then I think we're forever away.
Well, think I don't necessarily disagree with you.
think there's a lot of legacy code and applicable.
I mentioned mainframe, right?
There are a lot of different companies who are just at different stages of their maturity
in their organization.
Some are big, some are small.
And not all of them are going to get there at the same time.
you're probably familiar with it, but there's this curve of like where people are at on
the acceptance of a particular product or problem.
Yes, yes, exactly, that's it is.
one thing that I think we have seen is people are running more production workloads now
with Pinecone.
Whereas in the past it has like it has been I don't want to say it has been less
production but we are seeing more people kind of latch on to that and doing stuff in
production.
ah And so as we see more and more of that like that's people like learning how to do this.
So like I'm saying like we're still very early in this
totally on the same page there.
And I think you're absolutely right, those workloads may or may not have anything to do
with LLMs.
Like we've solved, we've identified a new functional way of storing data and searching it.
And there are primary applications where that's valuable.
If you talk about RAG, we're talking about knowledge bases.
We're talking about semantic search, where we're talking about searching through tons of
attributes and fuzzy searching, free text searching that.
never really was that great to begin with.
mean, whole companies have made their entire existence to figure out how to actually do
this correctly.
And now we have a fundamental technology or understanding of how to do this fundamentally
at a principle level with raw mathematics.
do think that there is some coming around there.
And it will be interesting to see whether or not the companies that gravitate towards
needing vector databases are more and more in the alarm space or less and less as
companies figure out the value that they can extract from it.
ah So I guess it'll be interesting to see where Pinecones customers end up a few years
from now.
do want to quickly maybe ask you oh an opinion on I think one thing that has happened in
the last five years is companies having to LLMs being used during the interview process.
Yeah.
I don't know if I should just stop the question there and just let you say something, or
if I should specifically ask like, yeah, has this impacted Pinecones interviewing
practices?
And if yes or no, like are they seeing the use of LLMs intentionally by candidates?
Like, is it encouraged to be done ah or have you worked around trying to figure out how to
deal with the fact that?
these alarms will be used during the interviewing cycle.
in my experience, and I and at my last job, I did do a lot of also interviewing to hire.
And it's definitely a thing.
People use them.
um I did not use them.
It was not part of my interview process.
But I do think.
As long as you're setting the expectation of how and why you're using a tool, uh then it
makes more sense.
I don't think that anyone should be pretending they know something when they don't.
destroyed the whole industry there, just with that one statement.
I think just from a practical perspective, we use tools in our day jobs.
And so if I can't use cursor or cloud code to write code and show how I would do my actual
job, then it's really hard for an interviewer to understand how you're going to do your
job.
interesting personal opinion because, and I think this is a pattern for a lot of our
guests that come on this show that previously you were working at Amazon.
ah I don't know if it was AWS specifically.
So I don't know what it is with our podcast and like people like leave AWS after being
there for like four years or so.
I didn't actually look to see how long you were there.
And then then our new job for a couple of years and uh
then come on this podcast and have some really interesting things to say.
Uh, no spilling of the details.
They're just under five years.
a question, around the interviewing.
ah Did you see things already starting to be rolled out at AWS
During my almost five years I was interviewing people and it's a very rigorous, like you
go through training to learn how to interview and you've probably seen some of the
questions that we ask.
while I was there, there was no conversation, like I didn't have any conversations with my
leadership about when or how LLMs are allowed to be used.
during the process.
don't want to say it was early enough where it wasn't happening.
I'm sure it was happening, but it was not a part of my experience there during the
interviewing.
I don't want to know, think is the, uh, the joke I told.
I'll say this.
if you get through the interview round with us you were using an LLM and then you continue
to use an LLM in your day job for however long you're here until the day you leave and no
one finds out, was there any harm?
Um,
for me, it's been like using an LLM as part of my job has been embedded since she at GPT
came out.
at Amazon, not just AWS, but at Amazon, like we were tasked with figure out how to use
this.
Um, and it same thing at Pencon, like we're, we're tasked with figuring out how to use
these tools because everyone else is using them.
And if they're trying to use our products or they're trying to do stuff with
pine cone, then we need to know their experiences.
We need to know what the friction is, what's working, what's not working, all that kind of
stuff.
when I say I think it is okay as long as to use it during the interview process, as long
as the expectations are the same on both sides, it's because I use them every day.
I fully recognize like I'm in a special situation.
I work for a company that deals with this stuff, right?
And builds this stuff.
so this is actually why I like asking the question specifically from people that are
working at a company that's in and around the space where they're building tools or
support for things like it'd be a weird twist of fate where you're like, well, we don't
know how to deal with these these interviewer like these interviews where the candidate
comes in is using an LLM and like the product that they're using is using some sort of rag
that is has a vector database that's running on pine cone.
you know, that's a sort of like weird circle there.
where like probably something you should have thought about, it's good to realize, okay,
no, actually not only are our employees, but also are the developers that are utilizing
the product to embed in their own applications.
They're utilizing these tools as an important part of the flow, like expectedly.
So understanding how they're utilizing them is important for us to even design a better
application.
Yeah, exactly.
maybe I'll give you the moment in case there's anything that we left out here that you're
just like, I really need to share about this thing.
had a uh major pine cone release.
The best feature that has ever come out is about to drop one week from now.
I don't know what that is, but feel free to plug that
ah I don't have the next feature that's coming out.
And if I did, I probably couldn't say, so.
it's a cool technology.
So if you are a person who likes to uh understand like how things work and we have a lot
of really good content on the Pinecone blog about just kind of
search in general and like algorithms in general and if you're if that's the thing you're
into and
whether LLMs are here to stay or not, I do think that there is a unique innovation that's
happened here.
And outside of that, it's definitely worth learning.
So if this weekend you are going to spend some time rewriting whatever your favorite
JavaScript runtime is in a new language like Rust or Zig, just because you can.
Or an operator for Kubernetes, sounds like a better use of your time would be potentially
to uh invest in learning vector databases and why not use pine cone for that.
I agree with that.
I think upskilling in the long run.
So with that, can switch over to doing picks.
so my pick for this week is, do I put this?
I found that I often plug things into my computers and unplug them over and over again.
And I frequently get concerned about the reliability of the USB-C port, everything I have
is USB-C, especially like my YubiKey.
So I'm a big physical passkey user, I think too much about security, probably more than I
should.
so I...
spent a ton of money, more than I probably should, on buying magnetic USB-C connectors.
So if you're watching the video, this piece here is just magnetic, which just goes
together.
And you can just walk around with this.
Here's a UV key, my micro one.
And honestly, it just made it better.
plug in all my laptops, my cell phone, all my connectors that are sitting out have a
magnetic thing on it.
And it's just been great for the last few months.
I can't believe I waited so long to do this.
Is this magnetic piece like a protector so it's a cover when you're not using it or I
don't I don't understand.
so the piece is just a USB-C to USB-C connector.
So it's just USB-C and this is also USB-C and this part is two pieces.
So this gets connected.
So realistically, I walk around with this, just this side, which is not USB-C, it's just
like a magnetic piece and it just, they just snap together and they're interchangeable.
So like the same one I use for my cell phone, like I could, don't know no one's going to
be able to see this, but if I hold up my cell phone with the piece and I take my YubiKey,
like it will snap onto here.
ah But it's the same thing that also like if I want to charge my phone it's the same
connector.
And it's just been great honestly because like I don't have to worry about where on the
actual connectors anymore because they never pulled in or pushed out.
I had this problem like every single time I'm in the airplane I have those one of those
really annoying.
uh Mini phone three point five millimeter like splitters in the plane just for my
headphones and I like always break them on the plane like I will bash into them whatever
because.
you know the airplanes uh famous for giving you lots of room to move around in I I ruined
them and like this I just it would just come off honestly and it's
it reminds me of the old Mac connectors.
It's not USB-C, it's not lightning, but it was like, if you toggled it just a little bit,
it would come off as opposed to breaking off in the connector, right?
Do you remember that?
Okay then.
was somewhat jealous of people with the AC adapter connector, I think it was MagSafe or
something like that, to connect.
Yeah, and I don't know, my Apple got rid of it and they brought it back.
It seemed like they were onto something.
I do get that it falls off, but for me, I'm not using it for walking around with.
So it's like my USB key.
I'm on, I'm traveling somewhere, it's really annoying to stick it into my laptop and pull
it back out again.
This is like really easy swap.
I don't know what it was that I just like clicked for me.
Like I could actually do this.
I guess I never wanted to do it with like USB-A because it just seemed like such a legacy
technology all the time.
ah But now that everything's USB-C, like this has been absolutely fantastic.
I'm going to have to check it out.
Yeah, be prepared to uh I think this is like by Hansen or something like that.
I don't know some random brand on Amazon.
I'm sure it's ripped off from like another company that makes really good ones.
These are actually not cheap though.
So.
the same one, just a different logo.
Oh yeah, that's the thing is there's no even, I don't know if there's a logo on it
actually.
So like that's the most suspicious part.
So that's gonna be my pick.
You can't just buy one though.
You have to like go full in.
Cause like all your power adapters and everything have to be connected.
Otherwise you're like, well I have to pull out the plug in order to switch it.
So be prepared if that's gonna be your future.
Okay, Jenna, what did you bring for us?
My pick is...
I'll give you a little backstory first.
I have never really understood the allure of mechanical keyboards.
uh Back before microphones actually had like noise canceling on them, my mind's right
here, so back before microphones had noise canceling on them, uh they were very loud and
clicky and clackety and I just didn't understand them.
Anyways, a couple years ago I bought one and fell in love and...
uh I will show it to you.
It's right here.
uh This is not my, this one specifically is not my pick, but uh a couple of weeks ago I
bought another one uh because, well, first of all, I occasionally have wrist pain, so I
wanted a different layout and I also wanted a project.
And so I bought one that you actually had to put together.
And so I'm only part way through this,
Like I said, I wanted, I needed a project.
Like I spent enough time in front of my screen.
Like I could actually build something with my physical, like physical hands.
But it's, kind of nice to just have something, something else um that is not writing code
or being on a computer, but will still support my computer years.
So I got a different layout.
I got the keycaps.
I got different switches that I think they're a little bit different than the ones I have
here.
So I'm excited to kind of try it out figure out if I like this new one as much as I like
this one.
I thought for sure you were going to say that you bought it and you still don't understand
why people like mechanical keyboards.
Oh no, I mean, I'm definitely not like, a fanatic about it.
Like, people are obsessed.
be careful if you say that, we're gonna lose some viewers if uh you come out on the-
judgment, no When I was at Amazon, I wrote a blog post uh about mechanical keyboards.
I just kind of wanted to understand who uses them, who likes them, and which one do you
have.
uh Got a lot of opinions on there.
One of my friends commented, uh coworkers commented, and he's like, as soon as you start
building your own, then you've gone too far.
So I've gone too far.
mean, I get the ergonomics for
if you have some sort of physical pain, like you know that there's something wrong with
what you're doing or if you, I mean, it took me a lot of years to realize, wait, my whole
job revolves around my keyboard.
I probably should have one that fits me as best as I can and that includes, for me it was
a keyboard layout, I get totally the physical result, like actually having to push the
keys and whether or not that's problematic.
I have a thing for sound though and so I did some research on getting the quietest
keyboard possible and
A bunch of people said, yo, they make really quiet mechanical keyboards.
And I'm like, okay, sure.
So I probably spent like a whole bunch of hours going around to different shops, pushing
the keys on different mechanical keyboards in multiple countries and like going online and
like listening to audio clips of the mechanical keyboards.
And after that, all I conclude is those people have no idea what they're talking about.
Mechanical keyboards are not quiet in any way.
The quieter switches, like they're not, they're not quiet.
ah And I actually, my pick actually in a previous episode was my keyboard, which is uh
dedicated to be a silent keyboard.
So people can hate me all they want for that, but I still will not get mechanical
keyboards unless you have a physical element.
ah Cause then, you know, I get it.
totally do.
ah Yeah, I also went down both times.
I went down a rabbit hole trying to figure out which one should I get.
I didn't go quite that far.
I didn't actually go to physical stores.
There's not many here that sell what I was looking for here, but you're right.
They're still not quiet, even though I think I got one of the quieter sets of switches.
And the smoother ones that don't make as much of the clickety clackety, um there's still
some sound there.
I have to ask you, ah so what's the keyboard brand or model that you purchased?
So the one that I showed you is a Keychron Q1 Pro Wireless.
just is, I think it's like the 75%.
I'm holding it up for the people who are just Yeah.
It doesn't have like the number pad on the side.
So it's the 75 % layout, I think.
The new one that I got is an Alice layout.
So it's a little bit more rounded, that, where your hands are
I'm rotating my hands, Where your hands are a little bit in a more natural layout as
opposed to straight up and down like you would on kind of a regular keyboard.
And it's a little bit bigger too.
One thing that like I've noticed with this one here is it is a it's narrower.
It's 75 percent, so it's narrower.
And so like my hands are closer together.
the one other piece that I like about this brand specifically are this this these.
is that ah it's pretty hefty.
Like, this is several pounds.
ah And so it's solid.
I don't know, I just, I like the feel of Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's not gonna go anywhere if I
get like carried away.
I think we have probably like one guest per year on the show who calls out their
mechanical keyboard is there is their pick.
So you're in good company.
Yeah.
So with that, I think we'll call it the end of the episode there.
Thank you so much, Jenna, for coming on and being our target practice for today's episode.
Thank you so much for having me.
been a good conversation.
It has been, I've enjoyed it.
And I just want to thank personally Attribute one last time for sponsoring today's
episode.
And I hope to see all of our viewers and listeners next.